<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
	<properties>
		<author email="erik.dannenberg@bbe-consulting.de">
			Erik Dannenberg
		</author>
		<title></title>
	</properties>
	<meta name="keyword" content="mavento, maven, magento, site, quality reports, documentation" />
	<body>
		<section name="Project Documentation">
			<subsection name="Overview">
				<p>
					Maven can generate a static html site with project reports/source
					documentation for you, to do that invoke:

					<source>
mvn site</source>

					The site will be rendered in
					<b>/target/site</b>
					of your project root. Note that you will either need
					<b>phpDocumentor</b>
					in your system path or disable the phpDocumentor report in your
					pom.xml.
					<br />
					<br />

					The site descriptor is in
					<b>/src/site/site.xml</b>
					, you can add/remove pages to the site structure here.
					The
					<b>changes.xml</b>
					in the same folder provides a simple way to keep a changelog.
					<br />

					To edit the manual content have a look at the files in
					<b>/src/site/xdoc</b>
					. The dynamic pages like team, source repository, etc
					are created from the data in your
					<b>pom.xml</b>
					.
					<br />
					<br />

					It is possible to style the page via css overrides, put them in
					<b>/src/site/resources/css/site.css</b>
					. You can also create
					your own Maven skin to be used by all your projects.
					<br />
					<br />
					For more information on site generation refer to the Maven
					<a href="http://maven.apache.org/guides/mini/guide-site.html"
						target="_blank">documentation</a>
					.

				</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="Multi Module Project Sites">
				<p>
					Maven will generate the site for each module in it's target/site
					directory, to consolidate all the parts of the complete site
					you have to invoke an additional goal..

					<source>
mvn site site:stage</source>

					..will create a complete local site with working links in
					<b>/target/staging</b>
					. Take care to invoke the command from the parent project.

					<br />
					<br />
					Or..

					<source>
mvn site-deploy</source>

					..will deploy the complete site according to your configuration in
					the distributionManagement block of your pom.xml.
					Which is in most cases a web server.
					<br />
					<br />

					Both commands will also work for single module projects, though
					site:stage is a bit silly in that case.
				</p>
			</subsection>
		</section>
	</body>
</document>
