<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
	<properties>
		<author email="erik.dannenberg@bbe-consulting.de">
			Erik Dannenberg
		</author>
		<title></title>
	</properties>
	<meta name="keyword"
		content="mavento, maven, magento,maven-magento-plugin, magento-maven-plugin, magento deployment, magento continous integration, ci" />
	<body>
		<section name="Mavento - Magento development with Maven.">
			<subsection name="Overview">
				<p>
					Mavento is a project to build, test and deploy Magento projects
					with Maven.
					It was
					started to achieve continous integration for
					Magento
					projects,
					but
					has since matured into a solid toolbox for
					Magento
					developers of
					all kind.
					The magento-maven-plugin provides
					Magento
					specific goals
					which
					can be
					plugged into the Maven build life
					cycle
					or
					run from any
					shell.
					The
					magento-archetypes provide ready to run
					Maven
					projects
					configured
					for Magento development.
					<br />

					All projects are open source and can be found on
					<a href="https://github.com/edannenberg" target="_blank">github</a>
					.
				</p>
			</subsection>

			<subsection name="Why Maven?">
				<p>
					Imagine a world where every project can be configured, build,
					tested and deployed in exactly the same way.
					A world where any
					developer or user can simply checkout the project
					source, run the
					same
					single command and start working. A mystical place where
					dependencies, like the Magento core files, no longer need to
					pollute your source repository to get a repeatable build.
					<br />
					<br />

					Joking aside, such are the goals of Maven, a software project
					management and comprehension tool that aims at providing
					a uniform
					and easy build process. It is very popular in the Java
					world, but
					can handle any type of project,
					be it java, c++, php, ios, simple
					static html or even authoring a
					print book.
					<br />
					<br />

					Apart from this holistic approach, Maven follows the convention
					over configuration paradigm and has excellent dependency
					management,
					which is what makes Maven so different from build tools
					like ant or make. The benefits of Maven are substantial once you
					have to work/integrate with a bunch of different projects or your
					organisation grows.
				</p>

			</subsection>

			<subsection name="Features">
				<ul>
					<li>Keep your source files separated from the Magento runtime at
						all time.
					</li>
					<li>Consistent development environment between all involved devs.
					</li>
					<li>PHP code validation/unit tests via maven-php-plugin.</li>
					<li>Flexible automated Magento setup of vanilla or custom
						instances.
					</li>
					<li>Create snapshots of running Magento instances to be used as
						base for testing/development.
					</li>
					<li>Less boilerplate Magento code to write with ready to run module
						templates and code snippets.
					</li>
					<li>Multi module support for bigger projects. Reactorbuilds. &lt;3
					</li>
					<li>Dead easy project integration into CI servers like Jenkins.
					</li>
					<li>Automated project documentation/code quality reports.</li>
				</ul>
			</subsection>
		</section>
	</body>
</document>
